get up, house. must be some mistake.
- 起来 House - 搞错了吧
i specifically requested my wakeup startle three hours from now.
我特别要求过三小时后再让我惊醒的
some vip visitor. dean of medicine from your old hospital.
有贵客到 你以前那医院的院长
i've had dreams about this.
这一刻我曾经梦到过
i'm going to assume this is another one.
我就当这是另一个梦好了
get up.
快起来
i can refuse to see any visitor i want.
我可以拒绝接客的
tell the dean that i don't want to see her.
告诉院长 我不想见她
he said you'd say that.
他说过你肯定会这么说
he?
是他?
what's the hiring policy over there?
那边现在雇人的政策变了吗
all ass based?
看谁最傻吗?
i can get you out of here.
我可以帮你离开这儿
not unless that file has a file in it.
除非有白纸黑字的文件
judge's order for your immediate release.
法官已经批准即刻释放你
i had eight months added to my sentence two months ago.
俩月前 我被加刑八个月
the math is pretty basic. we have a crisis.
- 这可是最基本的加减法了 - 我们遇到一个难题
which is good news for you.
这对你来说可是好事儿
you're out tonight on conditional parole.
今晚你将获得有条件假释
the condition being that you're employed by me at ppth.
条件就是你来PPTH为我打工
no, thanks.
免了 多谢
you think it's a good idea for me to go right back to my old life?
你觉得让我回到过去的生活中 这对我好吗?
for either of us?
对我们大家又好吗?
your patient is two lungs in a box.
你的病人是放在箱子里的两片肺
and it only has 12 hours left.
现在只剩12小时
no pulse, no body.
没有脉搏 没有身体
no ability to answer questions.
更不能回答问题
it's your perfect patient.
这可是你梦寐以求的病人
i did pay for the room for the whole week, but...
尽管我已经交了整个礼拜的房钱 不过...
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生 第八季第2集
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生 第八季第2集
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 时间轴：潘潘达达
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻  译：给病人灌硝酸的王母娘娘 FFlonestar 校  对：不敢惹王母娘娘的酒囊饭袋 时间轴：潘潘达达
(foreman) donor's an 18-year-old college kid back from hofstra.
捐赠人是霍夫斯特拉大学一名18岁的学生
goes to a homecoming party with his buddies,
和朋友一起参加返校节舞会
hops on his motorcycle, ends up an organ donor. asystole in the e.r.
跳上摩托车 下来时就成了器官捐赠人 在急诊室心脏骤停
no pulse. no blood circulating.
没有脉搏 血液也不循环
his heart, liver, kidneys were all toast.
他的心肝肾都完了
surgeons had the recipient on the table when they realized the lungs had increased airway resistance.
医生在进行移植手术时 发现肺部气道阻抗增加
the team closed her up, put the lungs in suspended animation.
于是又给她缝合 把肺进入假死状态
buys 24 hours to fix it, 12 of which have passed.
为病人争取了24小时的时间 现在已经过去一半了
we still have no clue what's wrong.
依旧找不出问题所在
nice painting.
画不错啊
blues and greens.
蓝蓝又绿绿
calming, but with a hint of nurturing.
令人平静又带着一丝生气
totally offsets the stench of suffering and death.
完全中和了这地方痛苦和死亡的臭气
where's my patient? we need to not talk.
我的病人呢 我们得默默对视一下
icu isolation room.
在ICU隔离室
the transplant team will meet you there with updates from the past two hours.
移植小组的人会在那儿等你 汇报过去两小时内的最新情况
great. take this.
很好 拿着这个
how about you drop it in your office?
放到你办公室去如何?
i completely understand
我完全理解
and almost respect your desire to appear to be dean of medicine,
也基本尊重你想要成为院长的心愿
given that your title is dean of medicine. on the other hand...
鉴于你的头衔就是院长 不过另一方面
seriously?
这是真的吗
get this straight.
你听好
you break the law, you go back to jail. scam extra vicodin, back to jail.
触犯法律 回监狱去 偷止疼片 回监狱去
flout my authority, make the hospital look bad,
蔑视我的权威 令医院丢脸
back to jail.
就给我回监狱去
i own you.
你得听我的
yes, massa.
遵命 主人 (massa专门用于黑人称呼主人)
see, that would be an example.
瞧 这就是个例子
when did cuddy leave?
Cuddy什么时候走的
she gave her notice the day after your incident.
你出事转天 她就通知院方了
took a job-- don't need the details.
- 接了另一份工作 - 细节不用说了
(foreman) ortho needed more space. you're this way.
骨科的地方不够用 你这边
where's my stuff?
我的东西呢
(foreman) no idea.
不知
what about my team? pathetic.
- 我的人呢 - 真可悲
the first thing you said to me was you don't want your old environment.
你见到我第一句话 就是 不想再回到以前的环境中
the fourth thing you said was, "where's my old environment?"
可现在你说的第四句却是"我的过去都在哪儿"
it's been a year.
已经一年了
taub, chase, thirteen all moved on. the world does that sometimes.
Taub Chase 13都已经开始新生活了 万物有时就是如此
no, it doesn't. here's your new office.
- 不 才不是 - 这是你的新办公室
and there's your new team.
还有你的新团队
i'm not interested in another department's sloppy seconds.
我对其他部门的差劲二等品没兴趣
i'm not sloppy seconds. 3:00 a.m.
- 我不是差劲的二等品 - 现在是凌晨3:00
if foreman had called you in from home, you wouldn't have pressed clothes,
如果Foreman把你从家里找来 你就不会穿着整齐的衣服
coiffed hair, and makeup, which means you were already here in the hospital.
头发一丝不乱 还化好妆 这就说明你早早就等在医院里了
yes, i was on call for neurology.
是的 我是神经科的值班医生
well, if that were true, you'd be working right now
如果是真的 那你现在就该在忙工作
and unavailable to help.
没功夫帮我
which means that you're hanging out in the hospital pretending to work.
所以呢 你就是在医院闲逛 假装一副很忙的样子
which means you're not just a reject, you're a cowardly reject
也就是说 你不仅没人要 并且很没用
who was trying to hide her rejectedness from someone.
试图在别人面前掩盖自己不受待见的事实
i am not a reject. then go back to neurology.
- 我不是的 - 那就回你的神经科去啊
i can't.
我不能
i punched my attending.
我打了主治医生
ards secondary to trauma is our leading hypothesis.
创伤造成的急性呼吸窘迫综合征(Ards) 是我们现在的主要假设
fio2 is 93%--
吸入氧浓度是93%...
prison!
坐牢
sorry. i thought i heard everyone else think that.
不好意思 我以为你们都在这么想呢
i was in prison, you see.
我是坐过牢哈
it was a long time ago, but still you're curious.
虽然过去很久了 但你们依然很好奇
never was raped, not raped-raped.
没被爆菊 没有人强迫我
well, raped-raped, but not raped-raped-raped.
虽然不用强迫我 但还是没有人来狠狠采摘我的小菊花
well, now that we've got that completely behind us.
好的 现在这一页正式翻过去啦
sorry, dr. house, welcome back.
抱歉 House医生 欢迎回来
is there cake?
有蛋糕吃吗
any alveolar exudate?
有没有肺泡渗出?
(simpson) no. lungs are dry.
没有 肺部很干燥
well, then it's not ards.
那就不是Ards
it's the autumn. it's tick-borne disease season.
现在是秋天 是蝉传疾病的季节
ehrlichiosis causing bronchiolitis.
埃里希体病导致细支气管炎
you'll appreciate that i left the "idiots" subtextual.
我没话里骂你"傻子" 已经算你走运了
blood smear was clear, and we "idiots" treated with broad spectrum antibiotics.
血液抹片没有问题 我们这些白痴给病人用了广谱抗菌药
cocaine. tox screen was clean. dead men don't pee.
- 可卡因 - 毒性检测没问题
tox screen tests for metabolites in the urine.
毒性检测是要化验尿液中的代谢物
coke never got past the lungs.
可卡因从来都不从肺部走的
also explains the motorcycle crash.
这同时也能解释车祸的起因
idiots.
白痴
let's get the lungs on treatment.
我们快治疗肺部吧
(house) great idea. unless you're wrong.
好主意呢 除非你是错的
and by you, i mean me. then this treatment will burn holes in the lungs.
我说你 其实是指我自己 这治疗会让肺部变成筛子的
i'd call you idiots again, but at this point i'm starting to doubt whether you understand what i mean by the word.
我很想再深情地呼唤你一声白痴哥 不过我对你是否能听懂我的话表示怀疑
kato.
小日本
get black beauty and meet me out front.
去叫黑美人 我们前面碰头
we're gonna find the dead kid's stash.
咱们把这死孩子的私货都给翻出来
since an 18-year-old with organ donor
既然是一个18岁的器官捐赠人
on his license is not a cancer patient,
驾照上又没写他得了癌症
i'm figuring the recipient is a lifetime member of the wilson cares too much club.
我想接受移植的人 一定是Wilson"大爱没边儿"俱乐部的永久会员
excellent deduction. you're the reason i'm out of the big house.
- 真是精辟的推断 - 是你让我出来的
doesn't quite make up for never visiting--
并不能弥补你不去看人家
springing you was foreman's idea.
让你出来是Foreman的主意
i wasn't convinced until simpson failed three times. it amounts to the same thing.
- 我本来不确信的 直到Simpson三次都失败了 - 那还不是一个意思
you wanted me back. see, i knew you'd over-interpret it.
- 你想要我回来 - 瞧 我就知道你会过分解读
strong, emotional reaction.
强烈的感情反应
i guess that's what a lifetime membership gets you.
我想这就是永久会员的能耐所在吧
how's your wrist? healed, thank you.
- 你的手腕怎么样了 - 好了 谢谢
i was wrong.
是我错了
i went to prison. i paid the price.
我进了监狱 接受惩罚了
[wilson's pager beeps] you're a changed man. i said i was wrong.
- 你现在重新做人了 - 我是承认自己错了
i didn't say i changed. i haven't. neither have you--
没说我重新做人 我怎么可能 你也不行啊
analyze it however you like. we're not friends anymore.
随你分析 我们不再是朋友了
what can i do?
我能怎么办
my chest. angina's back.
我的胸口 喉炎又发作了
upping the nitro should knock it back down.
增加一点硝酸或许能缓解一下
sis and i were talking, trying to figure out
姐姐和我刚才在聊 我们一起
how many hospital sleepovers we've had.
在医院度过了多少个夜晚
it definitely started with the great mastectomy of 2001.
一开始就是2001年的乳房切除
god, i miss my boobs. they were spectacular.
天啊 我好想念我的胸部 她们是那么美
is there a chance of locating another donor?
有可能联系到其他的捐赠人吗
it's unlikely.
不太可能
especially since, with the extent of the emphysema, she needs a double lung.
特别是因为气肿的范围 她需要有两片肺才行
how are you doing? better already.
- 你还好吗 - 好多了
it's a good thing that worked. i was gonna make you bring me a bottle.
好在起作用了 我差点就让你给我拿瓶酒来了呢
oh, lighten up, sis.
别一张苦瓜脸 妹妹
you know, the least you could do is laugh at a dying lady's jokes.
好歹你可以配合一下这个快死的女人的笑话吧
your drinking wasn't funny then, and it's not funny now.
以前你喝酒就让人笑不出来 更别说现在了
because you're not dying.
因为你不会死的
the hospital brought in a consultant to work on the lungs.
医院请来了一位顾问 解决肺部的问题
do you know him? is he--is he good?
你认识他吗 他厉害吗
he is an excellent doctor.
他是非常出色的医生
we probably shouldn't be turning up unannounced like this.
我们或许不该就这么不请自来
their son just died.
他们的儿子才刚死
bright side-- they're probably up weeping.
往好的一面看 他们也许已经哭完了
hey, we both assaulted our bosses.
喂 咱俩都PK过老大
it's like we're twins. i'd really rather not discuss it.
- 咱俩就跟双胞胎似的 - 这件事还是不提的好
okay, i'll go first. my boss dumped me. and yours what?
好吧 那我先说 我被老大给甩了 那你的呢
called you his china doll?
称呼你为他的中国娃娃?
joked about what a crappy deal you got for manhattan?
嘲笑你为了曼哈顿让人给宰了?
assumed you have a huge penis?
假设你是长了一根硕大的小弟弟?
i have no idea what flavor you are, so i decided to cover the spread.
我不知道你好哪口儿 所以就广撒网了
my mom's filipino, dad's korean,
我妈妈是菲律宾人 我爸爸是韩国人
and my boss grabbed my behind.
我老大抓了我的后面
behind what?
后面有啥?
oh, yeah, your-- grabbed your tushy.
噢 是啊 你的 抓了你的小屁屁
so now you're pretending to be on call
所以现在你假装自己要值班
so that your overly protective boyfriend won't find out that you got groped.
那样你过分保护的男朋友 就不会发现你被人咸猪手了
i don't have a boyfriend. it's my parents.
我没有男朋友 是我父母
if they found out what i've done, they'd be mortified.
要是被他们发现 他们会觉得颜面尽失的
your parents know your call schedule?
你父母知道你的值班安排?
i live with them.
我们住在一起的
right.
是啊
no issues there.
这很正常
i told you my son didn't do cocaine.
我说了我儿子不吸毒
druggies are not known for their honesty. trust me on this one.
吸毒鬼向来不是以诚实著称的 相信我
mr. weathers, i am sure you're right, but we need to be thorough.
Weathers先生 我相信您是对的 但我们必须得彻底查清楚
did your son ever smoke marijuana? he was an athlete.
- 您儿子有抽过大麻吗 - 他是运动员
took real good care of himself.
非常洁身自爱的
hey, take it easy. steve loved all that-- sorry.
- 嘿 注意点儿 那都是Steve的宝贝 - 抱歉
but we're on a clock.
可我们时间紧迫
i think he's about to throw us out.
我觉得他要把我们赶出去了
nope. his son is dead.
不会的 他儿子死了
the only way that has any meaning is if we fix the lungs and transplant them.
唯一让他儿子死得有意义的方式 就是我们治好那对肺 完成移植
it doesn't matter how much we piss him off as long as we find something.
只要我们能有发现 他气死也没关系
so go back there, piss him off,
所以您请继续 使劲儿气他
and find something.
挖掘好料
do you know any of the kids at the party with your son?
您认识和您儿子一起参加派对的人吗?
bunch of his high school buddies.
都是他的高中同学
they'd gotten really into poker,
他们很喜欢打扑克
decided to have an all-night game in brandon broome's basement.
想在Brandon Broome的地下室打通宵
i understand that we're in a hurry and that he's probably not going to throw us out,
我知道我们时间紧迫 他也许不会把我们赶出去
but maybe he should.
可或许他应该这么做
your son isn't wearing glasses in any of these pictures.
照片上你儿子没有戴眼镜
he just got them a couple of weeks ago.
他是几个礼拜前刚配的
because he was having headaches?
因为他头痛吗
answer the question before answering the door.
先回答问题 再开门
yeah, he was.
是的
you're right.
你说得没错
he was not doing cocaine.
他不是吸毒
he had a brain tumor.
他是脑瘤
don't bother. it's for me.
甭麻烦了 是找我的
turns out they monitor these monitors.
原来啊 他们会监控这些监控装置呢
thank you, officer.
谢谢你 警官
i thought the bracelet was decorative.
我还以为这脚环是为了戴着好看呢
my aunt had one just like it. wait a minute.
我姨妈就有一个一样的 我靠....
you're allowed to be at the hospital. you're allowed to go home.
你可以在医院待着 可以回家
that was made clear. dead kid's house was on the way to my apartment.
- 这都是跟你强调过的 - 那死孩子家正好在我回家的路上啊
assuming i got lost twice.
可能我迷路了两次吧
those consultants in my office are only costing the hospital
我办公室的那几位顾问 每待一分钟
100 bucks every minute i keep them waiting.
就会让医院花掉一百大洋
why didn't you just tell me what you were doing?
你为什么不先跟我说一声呢
i knew you were very busy being vaguely important.
我知道你正忙着在我眼里变得不重要呢
i might have cleared it with the cops. yeah, it's the word "might" that bumps me.
- 我或许跟警方澄清了呢 - 是啊 这一个"或许"就要了我的命了
but i'll run it by you next time.
不过下次我会跟你打声招呼的
house.
House
getting you out of jail was not a popular decision with the board.
让你出狱并不是董事会人人称赞的决定
i need you to solve this, and i need you to do it without making me
我需要你解决这个病例 同时也需要你不要让别人以为
look like i can't control you.
我管不了你
for both our sakes.
为了咱们俩好
disciplinary hearing should be fun.
纪律听证会应该挺有意思的
and the subsequent lingering black mark on your record.
以及在你的档案上留下抹不掉的黑点
i'm not worried.
我不担心
we have to wheel this out to the mri.
我们得把他推到MRI去
we should probably leave the body in the bag.
还是不要动尸体的好
there's a mass in the arm.
胳膊里有肿块
analyzing part of this tumor is gonna be quicker than a scan.
分析一下这个肿瘤 比扫描可快多了
so where's the next job?
接下来你要去哪儿高就啊
you worry about what people think of you,
你很在意别人对你的看法
thus the carefully maintained hair, clothes,
因此你的发型着装 都很小心翼翼
and parental secrets.
还有父母的小秘密
the only way that you don't worry about this hearing is if you don't think
你之所以会不担心这次听证会
there's gonna be one.
是因为你觉得根本不会有听证会
the only way that happens is you leave princeton plainsboro.
而这样的唯一办法 就是你离开Princeton Plainsboro
i had a video interview with chicago yesterday.
我昨天和芝加哥那边视频面试了
it went well.
很顺利
my money's on rhabdomyosarcoma.
我赌横纹肌肉瘤
chicago has a great program,
芝加哥有一个很不错的项目
and you're a dumbass.
而你是个蠢蛋
running away from home is a time-honored tradition,
离家出走是有史以来的光荣传统
but you're not doing it to flee your parents.
可你却不是为了逃避父母才这样做
you're doing it to protect them.
你这么做是为了保护他们
that's an insult to everything teen prostitutes have worked for.
这对那些辛苦工作的"嫩妓"来说 可是侮辱
time to grow up and come clean.
是时候像个大人坦白一切了
you're right. i should just drive my car into their living room and tell them.
你说得对 我应该开车撞进他们的起居室 大声告诉他们
didn't it turn out that he'd stolen the hot dog cart?
最后不是发现他偷了热狗车吗
no, borrowed. bobby was very insistent on that point.
不是 是借的 Bobby对这一点非常坚持
seems like someone's feeling better. no more chest pain.
- 看来有人心情不错啊 - 胸口不疼了
i haven't heard the name bobby in a long time. how's he doing these days?
Bobby这个名字我都很久没有听到过了 他最近怎么样
i don't know. we're not in touch. and don't even pretend like you're not relieved.
我不知道 我们没有联系 别假装你没有松一口气
you never liked him.
你一直都不喜欢他
bobby is an incredibly fun, great guy. just not a great influence.
Bobby是个很风趣 很好的男人 只不过不是个好榜样
i would have gone with "colossal drunk."
我更倾向于"大酒鬼"
i was gonna leave that implied, but, yes, colossal drunk.
我本来不想暗示这个的 不过 是啊 酒鬼
what? it's good for a couple to share a hobby.
怎么了 两口子有共同爱好多难得啊
your catheter bag is empty, despite taking in 200 ccs of fluids.
你的尿袋是空的 虽然你摄取了200CC的液体
i'm gonna have to dial back the nitro.
我不能再给你用硝化甘油了
won't her chest pain come back? we don't have any choice.
- 她的胸痛不会出现了吗 - 我们也没办法
the nitro is dropping the blood flow to your kidneys.
硝化甘油会让你的血液流进肾脏里
they're shutting down.
你的肾脏不工作了
this is so our song.
这真是属于我们的定情曲呢
my patient is running out of time.
我的病人快要没时间了
not worried.
一点不担心
my team is confirming the diagnosis as we speak.
就在咱说话这阵儿 我的小队就正忙着确认我的诊断呢
i want to be understanding.
我本想表现得通情达理一点
it's your first day back-- see? i smell empathy.
- 毕竟这是你回来的第一天... - 瞧吧 我已经闻到你感同身受的味道了
you should remember all the good times.
你应该回忆回忆我们一起度过的好时光
like when i gave you that necklace that you just dumped in the ocean.
比如那次吧 我给了你条项链 结果你直接扔海里去了
what were you thinking? my heart will go on
真是的 你当时想什么呢?
house, i haven't forgotten our friendship.
House 我一点都没忘了咱们的所谓友情
for every good memory, there's a slew of bad ones.
因为每一段美好的回忆 都伴随着一串糟糕的回忆
come in. come in.
- 进来
paraneoplastic syndrome's out. the lung donor didn't have cancer.
不是副瘤综合征 肺脏捐献者没有得癌症
tell that to the tumor that i found in his arm. that mass wasn't a tumor.
- 跟我在他胳膊里找到的肿瘤说这话去呀 - 那个不是肿瘤
it was coagulated plasma. e.r. pumped him full of it.
只是凝结了的血浆 急诊室在抢救的时候给他大量输入过
i.v. leaked into his arm. i even did a complete mri.
点滴渗漏进了他的胳膊里 我连全面核磁共振都做过了
no cancer anywhere.
哪里都没找到癌症
we've got nothing.
我们又回到起点了
just 'cause it wasn't a tumor
就算不是肿瘤
doesn't mean it didn't mess with the lungs.
也不能说明他的病就对肺没影响
they're reacting to something in the plasma.
这些症状是针对血浆中的某些物质出现的
but every unit of plasma can have up to 25 contributing donors.
但是每单位的血浆都可能含有 多达25位捐赠者的血液成分
we need to track down all of them.
我们得一个个找
still.
挺好的了
it's not as bad as a thousand people going down in a gigantic boat, right?
总比一千人和一艘船一起沉了的好 是吧?
my heart will go on.
我心永恒哟
no, you can't leave the hospital.
不 你不准出医院大门一步
25 donors contributed to the plasma
25位捐赠者的血液成分
that the lung donor got.
组成了输入肺脏捐献者体内的血浆
my team cannot track down and interview them all in six hours.
我的小队没办法在六小时之内 把他们全部找到并且询问一遍
i vouch for you to the cops, you take some parole-violating detour
如果我跟警察打过保证之后 你准又得偷偷干点破坏假释的勾当
celebrating your freedom, justified, of course,
庆祝一下重获自由什么的 而且还觉得自己蛮有理
by some absurd theory connecting it to the case.
因为不知怎的那也和病例相关了
you asked me to ask you.
你让我来问你
was that just so you'd enjoy saying no?
难道只是为了享受说不的快感?
i don't trust you, house. i can't.
我不相信你 House 我不能相信你
actually you have to.
其实吧 你必须得信我
not absolutely. not outside the walls of this hospital.
并非全信 一出医院大门以后尤其不信
fine, then give me a team i don't have to put in quotation marks.
好啊 那就给我一个真真正正的小队啊
use the people already on the case.
利用已经在负责这个病例的人吧
give me chase, taub, thirteen. we don't have the money to pay them.
- 把Chase Taub和13还给我 - 我们没钱请他们回来
it went to interior designers, i understand.
钱都花在重新装修上了嘛 我懂的
you only have park because she's on neurology's tab.
你能有朴医生还是因为是神经科在付人家工资呢
you are making minimum wage. i am?
- 你现在只能拿标准底薪 - 我还有薪水?
get out of my office, please.
现在请离开我的办公室
what do you got?
找到什么了?
number three went to a baseball game the day before he donated.
三号在献血前一天去看了场棒球赛
boredom is not transmissible.
无聊是不传染的
he ate a bag of peanuts, and peanut proteins would be.
他吃了袋花生 花生蛋白可是会的
if our donor had an allergy,
如果我们的捐献者过敏的话
it could explain the lungs. nice.
- 肺的状况就有解释了 - 不错哟
what?
什么不错?
(house) nothing. don't start that.
- 没什么 - 少来这套
(house) start what?
少来哪套?
i'm enjoying our conversation. the repartee.
人家只是喜欢跟你讲话嘛 斗斗嘴什么的
there was no repartee. that was repartee.
- 谁跟你斗嘴了 - 这就是斗嘴
i'm not doing this for you.
我现在跑腿可不是为了你
i'm doing it to help my patient.
是为救我的病人
it's just good to hear your voice.
我就是喜欢听你的声音
good-bye.
白白了您呐
that's my whiteboard. i need it.
这是我的白板 我要搬走
and he really doesn't care how the cast comes off.
而且他才不管石膏要怎么拿下来呢
dr. foreman warned us that you'd try something.
Foreman医生早就警告我们说你会来捣乱
told me to call him if you did.
还说你一捣乱就给他打电话
i'd like to do that.
我现在就要打了哟
i'll take this outside.
我还是去外面接好了
(park) donor six traveled to thailand around khorat.
献血者六号去过泰国呵叻高原一带
region was endemic with dengue fever.
那地区流行登革热
good.
很好
yeah. (park) alcohol.
- 说 - 酒精
well, you'd have to be pretty drunk for it to affect a pool of plasma.
如果想要影响到血浆的话 那这酒可真得喝不少
these guys have got that covered. acute etoh ingestion could have--
他们喝的还真不少 大量摄入酒精可能造成...
hey, paint around them!
嘿 刷油漆的时候绕过它们行不行?
they're not hurting anyone! who's painting?
- 它们碍你们什么事了吗 - 谁在刷油漆?
(park) the crew's just starting.
这帮人刚刚开始
paint fumes didn't cause contamination.
雾状油漆也许并未造成污染
but maybe the old paint did.
但是以前在上面的油漆却有可能
they scraped off the underpass, probably because it contains...
他们刮掉原来的漆重上 很可能就是因为原来的漆里含有...
(both) lead.
铅
chest pain back? worse this time.
- 胸口又开始疼了? - 这回更厉害了
is there any way to take the edge off?
能不能帮我止止痛?
we're still working on the lungs.
肺还没准备好
we should know soon.
但应该快有结果了
soon is good.
赶紧点吧
how's the chelation going?
螯合治疗做得怎么样了?
reverend moon started it about 20 minutes ago.
金将军二十分钟前开始动手了
you missed lunch tracking down the plasma donors.
为找血浆捐献者你午饭都没吃吧
got you a reuben from the cafeteria.
给你在楼下自助餐厅买了鲁本三明治
thanks.
谢了
lead exposure's a nice diagnosis. i hope it pays off.
铅中毒这个诊断不错 希望是对的
it will.
就是对的
i appreciate your confidence, but she's not really--
我欣赏你的自信 但是她...
oh, no, she could die.
哦 不是说她 她可能会死掉的
but technically it will still pay off.
不过技术上来说 还是有用的嘛
even if your patient dies, someone will get the lungs.
因为就算你的病人死了 还有其他的病人啊
you really haven't changed.
你还真的是死性不改啊
but i've given up red meat.
但是我现在已经不吃红肉了 (鲁本三明治里有牛肉)
what round of chelation is this? fourth.
- 这是第几轮螯合了? - 第四轮
are you checking up on me or on house?
你是在监视我呢 还是监视House呢?
this case.
我监视的是这个病例
unique situation. oxygenating?
情况特殊嘛 氧饱和度?
98%. airway resistance down.
98% 气道阻抗已消失
great. is house okay?
很好 House还好吧?
i have no idea.
我怎么知道
dad, what are you doing here? got your text.
- 爸 您来干什么? - 收到你的短信了
i brought you some of your mother's gomguk. what text?
- 给你带了你妈做的白菜汤 - 什么短信?
the one asking me to bring you some dinner.
就是你说让我给你送晚饭的那条呀
i went by neurology.
我到神经科去了一趟
the secretary said you were on leave.
秘书说你休假了
i'm consulting on this case. unique situation.
我在忙这个病例 情况特殊
it looks very complicated.
看起来真复杂啊
you can help with that?
你连这个都能帮上忙?
lungs are crashing. i have to go.
肺快不行了 我得赶紧去了
bye.
再见
(foreman) increasing to 100% fio2.
注入100%气体混氧
saline flow is down to 10 ccs.
盐水输入速率降至10毫升每秒
blockage? clot in the line? chelation is making it worse.
- 有梗阻? 输液线路里有堵塞? - 螯合让情况变得更糟了
it means we were wrong about lead.
也就是说铅这条我们想错了
hold the analysis and help me save this thing.
别分析了 先帮我把这玩意救回来
saline's flushing it forward but getting no return.
盐水灌流顺利但无回循环
one-way valve. vasospasm.
单向肺瓣反映 血管痉挛
if you're right, calcium channel blocker should relax the artery.
如果你的推断正确 钙阻流可以疏通大动脉
the lungs have no nervous system. will that still work?
但肺没有神经系统啊 那样还会有用吗?
we'll know soon.
我们很快就能知道了
saline flow's rising.
盐水循环率在上升
vasospasm's relaxing.
血管痉挛消失
left lung is pinking up.
左肺恢复正常颜色
good job.
干得好
right middle lobe isn't.
但右肺没有恢复
nothing.
没反应
we killed part of the lung.
我们把一个肺叶搞坏了
page dr. pinto stat to the cath lab. we're going to the cath lab?
- 呼叫Pinto医生立即到导管室 - 我们为啥要去导管室?
are you thinking that maybe-- what? who?
- 你是不是觉得... - 谁? 我们吗?
one dead lobe means four alive ones.
一个肺叶坏掉了 不还有剩下四个好着吗
it means enough to transplant with a side order of dead tissue that we can test.
这就说明不光剩下的还够移植 而且咱还多了检验的组织样本
it makes sense. unlike you stealing my phone.
有道理 不像你偷我手机的时候
you have unlimited texting.
你有不限条数的短信包月嘛
until your parents know, you will never see that punch for what it really was.
如果你爸妈不知道 你永远不会明白那一拳的真正意义
your february 4th.
你的二月四日
sri lankan independence day.
斯里兰卡的独立日
i told you i'm korean and filipino.
说过了我是韩菲混血
and i told you i wasn't listening.
说过了我根本没在听
by my actions.
用我的行动表达的
violence isn't an appropriate way to handle conflict. it was a moment of weakness.
暴力并非处理争端的正确方式 那只是一时的软弱而已
you barked at me, picked a fight with a painting crew.
你朝我大喊大叫 还差点和刷油漆的一帮人吵一架
maybe it's time to recognize it's not a character flaw.
也许是该认识这不是什么人性弱点的时候了
maybe it's your character. pinto! house.
- 可能只是你的个性不好 Pinto! - House
embrace your inner bitch.
拥抱你内心的泼妇吧
so why did chelation make the lungs worse?
为什么螯合治疗让肺的状况变得更差了呢?
we got about five minutes till pinto gets back.
Pinto回来之前我们只有五分钟
give me a hand with this. no.
- 快来帮把手 - 不
i tracked down another bag of plasma from the batch they used on the donor.
我找到了他们给我们的捐献者 用的那批血浆里的另一袋
negative for all our other exposures.
任何毒素都没有
sarcoidosis could be inflamed by the treatment.
我们的治疗手段可能引发硬皮症
i am a cripple in need of assistance.
我是个需要帮助的瘸子啊喂
transplant team ran an a.c.e.
移植团队做过血管紧张素转换酶检查了
negative. it's mine. and it's your job.
- 阴性 - 这是我的椅子 而你是我手下
my job is to assist you in curing the lungs. this chair will help me do that.
- 我的工作是协助你把那肺治好 - 这能帮我把肺治好
what if the scrapings from the bridge
也许桥上掉下来的残渣里
contained other heavy metals like beryllium or asbestos?
含有其它有害物质呢 比如铍或者石棉?
chelation for lead wouldn't have made them worse.
但针对铅的螯合治疗 并不会让这些症状变得更严重
but...
不过...
maybe the problem isn't a heavy metal from outside.
可能问题并不是出在体外的重金属上
it's inside. but it's not leaving the body like it's supposed to.
而是体内的重金属未能及时离开身体
it's stuck.
它被困住了
iron.
铁
the donor had hemosiderosis. his body wasn't disposing of iron.
- 捐献者有血色素沉积症 - 他的身体无法正常处理铁元素
massive amounts choke up the lungs.
大量沉积搞坏了肺
then our chelation would wreak havoc because it picks up too much stuff.
而螯合治疗让状况更糟 是因为它吸收的物质太多了
go stain the dead lung tissue for iron.
去坏死的肺部组织里找铁元素吧
i'm sorry, young lady, i simply will not help you steal this chair.
对不起 小姐 我就是不能帮你偷这把椅子
pinto. house.
- Pinto - House
she can barely catch her breath.
她气都上不来了
lungs ready yet?
肺准备好了吗?
we had a small setback. we're testing for iron overload.
出了点小问题 我们正在检查铁元素沉积
i thought it was lead. this is not an exact process.
- 我以为是铅呢 - 这不是个能完全确定的诊断步骤
your small airways are collapsing.
你的支气管在崩溃
you're not getting enough oxygen.
你得到的氧气不够
i'd like to try forcing an oxygen-rich slurry into your lungs.
我想尝试把富氧的半液体灌进你的肺里
it should open up the airways and buy you some time until the lungs are ready.
这样可以打开你的气管 在移植准备好之前为你争取时间
fluid? in my lungs?
把液体灌进肺里去?
sounds like drowning.
那不是要淹死人吗?
it is.
就是像那样的
gonna hurt, isn't it?
会很疼吧?
yes. a fair amount.
对 是会挺疼的
no.
不
i'm done.
我受不了了
(wilson) house, the nurses saw you come in.
House 有护士看到你进来了
enter.
进来呗
it's a bathroom.
这是厕所好吗
ah, explains the hole in this chair.
哦 我就说椅子上咋还有个洞
god, i missed doors.
天啊 我好想念有门的厕所啊
and air freshener.
以及空气清新剂
now go away.
现在一边凉快去吧
i'm waiting for some test results.
老子等测试结果呢
my patient signed a dnr. she's giving up.
我的病人签了拒绝抢救同意书 她要放弃了
looks like someone else will be getting the lungs.
看来这肺的确要给别人了
making this yet another interaction with you in which i get nothing.
让我又一次在和你的交流中一无所获
it's not my fault you can't handle your patient.
你管不了你的病人 这又不是我的错
she said she's done.
她说她受够了
i spent half an hour trying to change her mind, but she'd made her decision.
我花了半小时想劝她改变主意 但她决心已定
i accepted that. it's called respect. well, what's after respect?
- 我接受这点 这叫做尊重 - 好啊 那尊重之后呢?
you find another angle.
你再找个新角度
you hold her hand, get the sister to beg,
握住她的手 让她妹妹求她
stick your fingers in your ears, pretend you can't hear.
用手堵住耳朵 装着你听不见
you do whatever it takes. oh, whatever it takes.
- 你要用尽一切手段 - 啧 用尽一切手段
thanks, house. i hadn't thought of that.
谢了 House 好像我没想过这点似的
what are you testing for? hemosiderosis.
- 在检查什么? - 血色素沉积症
i'm staining for excess iron.
在找铁元素沉积
promising.
听起来不错
when your dad showed up unexpectedly, house have a hand in that?
你爸怎么突然来了 是House搞的鬼吗?
i'm guessing he does things like that a lot.
我猜他一定经常搞这种事吧
his version of a compliment.
这是他表达对你赞赏的方式
i spoke to the head of neurology in chicago.
我跟芝加哥那家医院神经科的头头谈过了
i gave you a good recommendation. did you mention what happened?
- 给了你很中肯的推荐 - 你跟他说这边发生的事情了吗?
lawyers say i'm not allowed to.
律师说我无权提及这事
it works out well for everyone.
这样对大家都好
why exactly is that good for you?
这对你到底有什么好处呢?
excuse me?
什么?
i'm a talented physician, top 2% of my class.
我是个才华横溢的医生 班上的佼佼者
i'm an asset to this hospital, an asset you're about to lose to chicago.
这医院的一笔财富 而你现在就要把这笔财富拱手送给芝加哥了
you applied for the job. you asked me to call and recommend you.
你申请的那份工作 你让我给人家打电话推荐你
andrews is the one that should leave. he's the supervisor.
Andrews才是该走人的那个 他是我的上级
he touched me first. i can't discuss any of that,
- 他先对我动手动脚的 - 我不能跟你说这事
not before the hearing.
至少听证会之前不能说
but if you're having doubts about chicago, i can call them back.
不过如果你对芝加哥那边改主意了的话 我可以再给他们打电话的
no. thank you.
没有改 谢谢你了
dr. foreman?
Foreman医生?
would you look at this?
您来看一眼行吗?
iron? no.
- 铁元素吗? - 不是
white blood cells.
白细胞
classic presentation of infection. how the hell did we miss that?
- 典型的组织受感染之后的状态 - 我们怎么会漏过这个的?
(park) biopsy revealed white blood cell infiltrates.
活检显示了白细胞的性状
infection was right after all.
感染的推断是正确的
fresh fruit in prison is usually chicken. why aren't you more alarmed?
- 监狱里的新鲜水果 一般都用鸡肉代替了 - 你怎么一点不紧张啊?
we're running out of time. aahh, she's dying!
- 我们快没时间了 - 哇啊啊啊啊啊 她要死啦!
were you able to figure out what was wrong while i was screaming?
我尖叫的时候你想出来啥不对了没?
infection was the first thing that the transplant team treated for.
感染是器官移植团队着手进行的第一项治疗
which would have worked if the bacteria had been out in the open.
如果细菌暴露在外 那治疗早就起效了
if they're hiding inside the lung cells... i'm thinking brucella.
但是如果它们藏在肺泡细胞里... 我觉得是布鲁氏菌
and to wipe that out, you need special ops.
想要除掉它们 你需要特勤组
an intact immune system.
完好无损的免疫系统
but that's what white blood cells are.
但白细胞就是免疫系统啊
they're part of the immune defense force, like the infantry.
它们只是防御力量的一部分 就像步兵队
but those lungs need the air force and the marines,
但是这肺需要的是空军啊 海军陆战队啊
antibodies raining down from above.
抗体密集空袭啊什么的
antibiotics and ivig.
抗体和免疫球蛋白
did you use metaphors for your old team?
你跟你以前的手下也用这么多比喻吗?
or do you just think i'm particularly stupid?
还是你单纯觉得我格外蠢?
no, they were stupid too.
没呢 他们也挺蠢的
what are you doing here?
你来干什么?
i'm here for vanessa.
我来看Vanessa的
now is not the time, bobby. she asked me to come.
- 现在不是时候 Bobby - 她让我来的
right, doc?
是吧 医生?
actually, it was my idea.
其实这是我的主意
what? what were you thinking? she doesn't want to see him.
你在想什么啊? 她不想见他
when vanessa was ready to quit chemo, bobby's the one who got her to do one more round.
但是当Vanessa想要放弃化疗的时候 Bobby说服了她让她再坚持一轮
yeah, and then he got her drunk.
是啊 然后把她灌醉了
at least tell me you haven't been drinking today.
至少告诉我你今天没喝酒吧
i should go. yeah.
- 我走了 - 没错
hail, hail, the gang's all here.
好啊 大家都在这儿了
case is under control.
病例没啥问题了
it's me time.
现在是自我享受时段了
vanessa's gonna do the lung slurry.
Vanessa同意肺部灌入液体了
you were right to push me.
你逼我是逼对了
i needed that. thank you.
我需要你来那么一下子 谢谢
so we're good?
那么我们和好了吗?
it was good advice.
你只是给了点好建议
just came here to say thank you.
而我只是来说谢谢的
i like you. i have fun with you.
我喜欢你 我觉得和你在一起有意思
and, if you can honestly say that you don't like me,
而且 如果你真能问心无愧地说你不喜欢我
you don't have fun with me, i can accept that.
你跟我在一起没意思的话 我也能接受
but just do whatever you have to do to get over this.
但是赶紧怎么着把现在这个状况解决了吧
you can punch me in the face, kick me in the nuts.
打我脸也成 朝我蛋上来一脚也成
either/or. both seems excessive.
二选一啊 两个都来就过分了
the thing is, house...
你听好了 House...
i don't like you.
我不喜欢你
when did the discoloration start? a few minutes after i started the ivig.
- 什么时候开始变色的? - 就在上了免疫球蛋白的几分钟之内
means we're wrong about infection.
意味着感染这条我们又错了
and by we, you mean you. you screwed up the lungs.
什么我们 就是你 你把肺搞坏了
wrong about autoimmune, not cancer,
自体免疫疾病是错的 癌症也是错的
heavy metals, genetic issues...
重金属中毒 遗传因素...
increase peep. already maxed out.
- 增大滴入量 - 已经增到最大了
we're close to the point of no return.
我们快要被逼到绝路了
the lungs will never be viable for transplant.
这肺没办法做移植了
i need...
我需要...
i need ideas.
我需要点子
iga nephropathy.
肾小球肾炎
that's already ruled out.
已经排除了
lupus. no.
- 狼疮 - 不是
maybe we're just out of time.
可能我们只是没有时间了
we're out of time when we're out of time. when they die or she dies.
没有时间的时候才是没有时间 它们死了病人也就完蛋了
keep them stable as long as you can.
尽最大努力让它们活长久一点
i need to think.
我需要思考
the lungs are a smoker.
这肺是个烟鬼
you of all people should know better.
你总不该这么蠢的啊!
but the kid never smoked. he played poker.
- 但那个孩子不抽烟啊 - 他玩牌
who plays poker without cigars?
谁玩牌的时候不点根雪茄呢?
even if he didn't light up himself...
就算他自己不抽...
it was a rainy night. the windows were closed.
那天晚上又下雨 窗户都是关起来的
all parents think their kids are special.
所有的父母都认为自己的孩子很特别
and these ones were right. at least his white blood cells were special.
而他的父母还真就对了 因为他的白细胞很特别
they had on on switch for reacting to smoke, but no off.
它们对烟雾有反应 但这反应无法消退
when he inhaled small amounts of smoke, he had small problems. no one even noticed.
当他吸入少量烟雾的时候 他的身体出现了小小的问题 但没人注意到
big amounts of smoke, that's enough to trash a lung.
而大量烟雾呢 他的肺就完蛋了
as soon as he breathed in all that cigar smoke,
于是当他吸入足量的雪茄烟之后
he was a dead man.
他就已经要死了
the motorcycle accident was an unnecessary dramatic flourish.
摩托车事故只是个不必要的狗血结尾而已
eosiniphilic pneumonitis.
嗜酸球性肺炎
but the steroids would have treated for that.
但是类固醇应该会治好了的啊
i was right. not about anything medical,
我是对的 虽然医学方面不一定
but my metaphors were perfect.
但我的比喻用的无懈可击
we need to hit it harder.
我们需要更强力的打击
we need to carpet bomb, blitzkrieg.
地毯式轰炸 闪击
we need the nuclear option.
甚至是核武器
at some point you're going to say we need to radiate, right?
你啥时候准备说我们需要上放疗啊?
see, the metaphors work. but that'll destroy the good lung too.
瞧 我教会你比喻了 不过那样那好的大半个肺也就完蛋了
better to go with a strong cocktail of immunosuppressants.
还是强力的免疫抑制剂鸡尾酒疗法比较保险
won't be fast enough. wilson needs these lungs.
不够快 Wilson可急着要这肺呢
it's working.
起效了
he did it.
他成功了
i'm not going to chicago.
我不去芝加哥了
if you stay, we have to have a hearing.
如果你要留下 我们就得开听证会
i know.
我知道
dad...
爸...
do you have a minute?
您现在有空吗?
(simpson) thoracic cavity clear. ready for the donor lungs.
喉腔清空 准备植入新肺
thank god you called him.
感谢上帝 你给他打了电话
i wonder what happens now.
不知道之后会发生什么
she can handle it.
她能挺过去的
(foreman) house.
House
got something for you.
有东西给你
i found your stuff in storage.
在储藏室里找到你的玩意们了
this is all you get.
但这就是你的办公室了
ortho still has the outer office.
外边大间还是人家骨科的
well, that sucks.
哎哟 这可真烦人
where are chase, taub, and thirteen gonna sit? you're welcome, house.
- 等Chase Taub 13回来了之后他们要坐哪? - 不用谢 House
dinner later? i'll pick something up.
一会一起吃晚饭吗? 我路上买点
i heard about a good new vegetarian place.
我...我听说有家新开的斋菜馆子不错
screw that. i want a steak.
去他大爷的 老子要吃牛排
i'll meet you at your place at 8:00.
八点钟我去你家找你
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入